Bayes Theorem can get a little more complex.
贝叶斯定理也许会更复杂
Let's take a look at a small example and what we'll
我们来看一个简单示例
do here is we'll mess a bit with the prior probability.
我们将稍微调整先验概率
So again, we have Alex and Brenda in the office,
同样 办公室里有 Alex 和 Brenda
and we saw someone pass by quickly and we don't know who the person is.
我们看到有个人快速路过 但是不知道是谁
So let's say we look more carefully at their schedules and we
假设我们仔细研究了他们的日程安排
realized that Alex actually works from the office most of the time.
发现 Alex 大部分时间在办公室上班
He comes by three days a week.
他一周来三天
And Brenda travels a lot for work, so,
Brenda 经常出差
she actually comes to the office only one day a week.
她一周只有一天去公司
So initially, without knowing anything about the red sweater,
因此 一开始不知道红色毛衣的任何信息
all we know is that it's three times more likely to see Alex than to see Brenda.
我们只知道看见 Alex 的概率比 Brenda 要高三倍
Therefore our prior probabilities are 0.75 for Alex and 0.25 for Brenda.
因此 Alex 的先验概率是 0.75 Brenda 的是 0.25
And let's say that we have this happening throughout all the weeks,
假设一周都是这种情况
but now we use our extra knowledge which is that the person we saw had a red sweater.
现在再利用红色毛衣这一信息
The rule is still as before,
规则不变
as Alex wears red twice a week and Brenda wears red three times a week.
Alex 一周有两天穿红色毛衣 Brenda 一周穿三天
So, naively we would think that the real probabilities are not exactly
很明显 实际概率并非正好是 0.75 或 0.25
0.75 or 0.25 because Brenda wears a red sweater more than Alex,
因为 Brenda 穿红色毛衣的次数比 Alex 多
so they should be a little closer to each other.
因此概率应该更接近
Let's calculate them. So, we'll do the following,
我们来计算下这两个概率 我们将这么思考
let's think of the columns as weeks instead.
我们将列看作周
So, now for each five-day work week,
对于包含五天的每个工作周
Alex wears red twice and Brenda three times.
Alex 穿红色毛衣的次数是两次 Brenda 是三次
So, we colored the days they wore red.
用红色标注穿红色毛衣的工作日
Now, since we know the person wore red,
我们已经知道路过的人穿红色毛衣
we forget about the times that they didn't.
因此忽略两人不穿红色毛衣的工作日
So we have nine times someone wore red.
有九次某人穿红色毛衣
Six of them are Alex and three of them are Brenda.
其中六次是 Alex 三次是 Brenda
Therefore, among nine times we saw someone wearing red,
因此 在看到某人穿红色毛衣的九次当中
two-thirds of the times it with Alex and one third of the time it was Brenda.
2/3 的次数是 Alex 1/3 是 Brenda
Thus, our posterior probabilities are two-thirds
Alex 的先验概率为 2/3 即 0.67
or 0.67 for Alex and one third or 0.33 for Brenda.
Brenda 的为 1/3 即 0.33
So it looks like we did a little bit of magic.
整个过程似乎很神奇
Let's do this again in a more mathematical way.
我们再以数学方式分析一遍
We saw a person and initially all we know is that it's Alex with
我们看到一个人 一开始我们只知道
a 75% probability and Brenda with
有 75% 的概率是 Alex
a 25% probability since
有 25% 的概率是 Brenda
Alex comes to the office three times a week and Brenda once a week.
因为 Alex 一周来公司三天
But now new information comes to light which is that the person is wearing
现在有了新的信息 即此人穿红色毛衣
a red sweater and the data says that Alex wears red two times a week.
数据表明 Alex 一周有两次穿红色毛衣
So now we look at Alex.
我们来看看 Alex 的概率
What is the probability that he's wearing red?
他穿红色毛衣的概率是多少？
Since a work week has five days and the probability of him
因为工作周有五天
wearing red is two-fifths or 0.4.
他穿红色毛衣的概率是 2/5 即 0.4
And the probability of him not wearing red is the complement, so 0.6.
不穿红色毛衣的概率是余集概率 即 0.6
Same thing with Brenda, since she wears red three a week,
Brenda 也一样 因为她一周有三次穿红色毛衣
then the probability of her wearing red today is
因此今天穿红色毛衣的概率是 0.6
0.6 and the probability of her not wearing red is 0.4.
不穿红色毛衣的概率是 0.4
Now, by the formula of conditional probability,
根据条件概率的公式
the probability that these two will happen is
这二者发生的概率是
the product of the two probabilities P of Alex,
这两个概率的积
times P of red given Alex.
即 Alex 的概率乘以 Alex 穿红色毛衣的概率
Therefore, the probability of the person we saw is Alex and that they're
因此 看到的人是 Alex 并且穿红色毛衣的概率
wearing red is precisely 0.75 times 0.4.
正好是 0.75 乘以 0.4
We multiply them and put the result here.
将相乘的结果放在这里
We calculate the other probabilities in the same way,
按照相同的方式计算另一个概率
that probability of the person we saw is Alex and that he's not
看到的人是 Alex 且没有穿红色毛衣的概率
wearing red is 0.75 times 0.6.
是 0.75 乘以 0.6
The probability of the person we saw is Brenda and that she's wearing red,
看到的人是 Brenda 并且她穿红色毛衣的概率
is again the product of these probabilities,
也是这两个概率的积
which is 0.25 times 0.6.
即 0.25 乘以 0.6
And finally, the probability of the person we saw is Brenda and
最后 我们看到的人是 Brenda
she's not wearing red is 0.25 times 0.4.
并且她没有穿红色毛衣的概率是 0.25 乘以 0.4
And now here's where the Bayesian magic happens, are you ready?
现在就要用到贝叶斯定理了 准备好了吗？
We have four possible scenarios
有四个可能的场景
and you can check that these four probabilities add to one.
可以发现这四个概率的和为 1
But we know one thing,
但是我们知道一个事实
that the person we saw was wearing red.
即看到的人穿红色毛衣
Therefore, out of these four scenarios,
因此 在这四个场景中
only two are plausible,
只有两个是合理的
the two when the person is wearing red.
即穿红色毛衣的场景
So, we forget about the other two.
忽略另外两个场景
Now, since our new universe consists of only these two scenarios,
因为新的推理环境只有这两个场景
then the probability should be higher,
因此概率应该更高
but their ratio should still be the same with respect to each other.
但是相互之比应该不变
This means, we need to normalize them or equivalently,
因此我们需要对它们进行标准化
divide them by something so that they now add to one.
或者同时除以某个值 以便相加之和为 1
The thing we should divide them by,
应该除以的值是
is the sum of the two.
二者之和
So, our new probability of the person being Alex is the top one, namely,
因此此人是 Alex 的新概率为顶部的值
0.75 times 0.4 divided by the sum of the two,
即 0.75*0.4 除以二者之和
namely, 0.75 times four,
即 0.75*0.4
plus 0.25 zero times 0.6.
+ 0.25*0.6
This is precisely two-thirds or 0.67,
正好是 2/3 即 0.67
and now we can see that the complement is the probability that the person is Brenda,
可以看出余集概率是此人是 Brenda 的概率
which is one third or 0.33.
也就是 1/3 即 0.33
If we take Brenda's probability and divide it by the sum of
如果将 Brenda 的概率除以两个概率的和
both probabilities we can see that we get one third as desired.
可以看到结果是预期的 1/3
And that's it, that is Bayes Theorem at its full potential.
这就是贝叶斯定理的原理